### Contact

spmallick@bigvisionllc.com

www.linkedin.com/in/satyamallick (LinkedIn) graphics.ucsd.edu/~spmallick (Other) www.taaz.com (Company)

# Top Skills

Machine Learning Algorithms Computer Vision

# Languages

Hindi

**English** 

### Certifications

Computer Vision for Faces

## Honors-Awards

Cover of Journal of Structural Biology

Best Poster Award, UCSD Research Review

University of California, San Diego Departmental Fellowship

Ranked 17th, Higher Secondary Examination, State of Odisha, India.

Certificate of Merit, National Standard Examination in Physics ( 1997 ) , India.

### **Publications**

Real-Time Driver Affect Analysis and Televiewing System

Specularity Removal in Images and Videos: A PDE approach

Automated cryoEM data acquisition and analysis of 284 742 particles of GroEL

Isotropy, Reciprocity and the Generalized Bas-Relief Ambiguity

ACE: Automated CTF Estimation

# Satya Mallick

CEO at OpenCV.org

San Diego

# Summary

Dr. Satya Mallick was recently named one of top 30 Al people to follow on Twitter for 2017 by IBM's Al blog. He is the founder of Big Vision LLC, a San Diego, California based company that specializes in computer vision, machine learning, deep learning and artificial intelligence consulting services and products. He is also the principal author of a popular computer vision blog http://www.learnopencv.com.

Dr. Mallick is an accomplished computer vision and machine learning scientist and engineer. He has worked on a variety of problems including face processing (detection, recognition), object recognition using deep learning, computational photography, augmented reality, document analysis, 3D reconstruction, medical image processing, and 3D cryo-electron microscopy to name a few. He has published several research papers in top notch conferences and journals.

At Big Vision LLC, Dr. Mallick and his team work with companies to solve computer vision and machine learning problems that have huge real world impact in terms of speed and accuracy of algorithms, reduction in manual work, and identification and creation of intellectual property.

Prior to starting Big Vision, Dr. Mallick had co-founded and was the CTO (R&D) of Sight Commerce Inc. — a computer vision company that creates vision and learning solutions for the beauty and fashion industry. He oversaw research, design and implementation of computer vision and machine learning algorithms and systems.

Dr. Mallick did his Ph.D. from the University of California, San Diego.

Experience

### **Patents**

Method for editing multi-channel images

Methods for identifying, separating and editing reflection components in multi-channel images and videos

System and method for providing and modifying a personalized face chart

System and Method for changing hair color in digital images.

System and method for providing a face chart

### OpenCV

Chief Executive Officer
January 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Helping OpenCV grow!

## Big VIsion LLC

Founder / Partner

February 2014 - Present (6 years 7 months)

Big Vision LLC provides Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Deep Learning consulting services for a wide variety of application domains that include face processing ( detection, recognition ), object recognition, hand written text recognition, augmented reality, and video analytics ( counting cars , pedestrians ).

Sight Commerce Inc. / TAAZ.com Founder / CTO (R&D) August 2007 - August 2015 (8 years 1 month)

Kriegman-Belhumeur Vision Technologies (acquired by Dropbox)
Research Scientist
January 2007 - April 2007 (4 months)

University of California, San Diego Research Assistant December 2001 - September 2006 (4 years 10 months)

The Scripps Research Institute Research Assistant 2005 - 2005 (less than a year)

# Education

UC San Diego

Ph.D., Computer Vision · (2001 - 2006)

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur B. Tech, Electrical Engineering (1997 - 2001)

Ravenshaw College

High School · (1995 - 1997)

Kendriya Vidyalaya